we're gonna talk about about family and we're gonna talk about i don't even want to use the
word mental the words mental health because i know that that takes people some other place i
want to talk about soul solidity i want to talk about that i want to talk about the solidity of
your soul keeping your soul intact that's what i want to talk about okay you can get my shirt
at amanda land exports happy birthday to a hajmalik shabazz aka malcolm x um
and what up dj mel star and uh so we're gonna we're gonna talk about that let me just get this up here
this text um so um uh let's see will instagram let me post this up here okay so i am shadowband
can you hear me can you hear me i hope y'all will stick around for this conversation
it's not going to be about cheyenne dr cheyenne it's not going to be about gossip this is going to be
about um first of all let me just say this we have to exist in two consciousness and i know that that's
very difficult for some people because they can't even live in one consciousness we have two
consciousnesses at least that we need to have an awareness of the consciousness of the reality
that is happening here and the consciousness of the reality that we want to exist in and because
of an inability to do that we find ourselves caught up all the goddamn time this is why we're always
like i'm so busy or i'm so stressed etc because we we are not able to hold those multiple consciousness
and that's also why these motherfuckers are able to control us and that's by design so i'm not trying
to blame any of us it's by design it's just that we have to get out of that the number one way to get
out of that to get out of a limitation of the reality that you want to exist in is to take control of your
energy and of your frequency we have been taught that whoever your family is they deserve to have
control over your energy and frequency no matter if they protect it or not we have been taught
it's been written down honor thy father father and thy mother etc etc and the problem though is that this
disregards some real facts which is that your mother and father are not simply controlled by the love
for you your mother and father are controlled by many other aspects that are taking place in this world
so to suggest that by nature of them birthing you they deserve the right to harm you is simply
ridiculous caribbeans are very big on this we also need to remember that for many black people
our mothers and fathers were not even our mothers and fathers okay for many black people we are the
descendants of folks who may have had mothers and fathers that were slave owners right mothers and
fathers that were um that were their owner that that were their bosses etc etc we have many generations
of this particularly in the caribbean it like my great grandma my great grandfather on my mother's side
was the boss of my great grandmother who was his maid so this concept of honor thy father and thy mother
is very distorted and very skewed and it cannot be painted with a broad lens it simply cannot the same
way that even referencing that book the bible cannot be painted with a broad lens because we all know
that there are different versions of the bible that have been distributed to different parts of the
world and different groups of people etc etc none of which for the goal of enlightenment
so you know i want to talk about this because i put up a video of a brother who was talking about
the fact that many of us have had to separate ourselves from our families many of us have had to
just really cut it out and excise the cancer of our families from our existence to move forward
and for some people they just can't seem to grasp the difference between legacy and family for some
people their connectivity to economics as somehow more important than the protection of your soul
and spirit is um is paramount for them however that for those of us who are on a higher vibration who
are in a path of liberation and collective liberation understand that that is simply deeply problematic
there are folks that have had to remain in connectivity with family for simply the hope of safety and
structure however when we live in different societies not all societies treat family obligation and
responsibility the same way all right we don't protect each other in the same way we don't hold up
liberation for each other in the same way if you like my malcolm x shirt you can get it at amandlin
exports this was drawn designed by my by my hand so when we are talking about this concept and reality for so
many people of having to excise yourself from this familial structure that is harming you
we have to have a certain empathy and a certain awareness of the fact that your reality may not be my reality
okay so this woman responded and said sounds great when you're young and mad but it's hard out here on
your own there's tax there's toxic and damaging and then there's tough love and accountability i think
folks really need to know the difference before cutting off family especially family who did right by you
but you just don't like their tone you're not perfect either you'll see community over individualism
so this is somebody who is projecting this is somebody who very clearly has been cut off because of
their inability to present truth and perhaps to present care to somebody in a way that they desired
if someone says to you listen i hear what you're saying but the way that you're saying it is really
fucking with me you're gonna need to hear that or else just don't talk to them that person is
obviously saying is obviously projecting also because the truth of no one wants to no one wants to
separate themselves from love nobody some people are incapable of receiving love because of their trauma
however they don't want to have to separate it's just in their body however that woman's post was
something that i thought was worth discussing and sometimes people are like why do you discuss the
quote-unquote negative ones a lot of it is a lot of the reason is because that person represents
someone in every one of our lives every one of us knows somebody who thinks like that who hears your
truth and distorts it into something else who hears your truth and distorts it into what they don't want
to deal with and then you now are having to explain and defend your truth and i want to remind you
that it is not your place to distort and to defend a distortion of your truth young and mad being applied
to being grown and clear are not the same things for also we need to point out identifying harm
being disproportionately colored as mad or sensitive is one of the major ways that we create distance in our
families sometimes folks is young and mad and also it's like okay you young so this feels like mad right
now when you get older you get more wise it'll synthesize differently but right now yeah you young
and mad and i respect it be young and mad and all you can do is say i am not trying to harm you
and then show that in action as an adult when you have done the work of understanding your triggers
understanding your traumas understanding the cause of this someone replying to you saying this is harmful
to me as you're being young and mad is called a gaslight it's dismissive and it is deeply embedded
embedded in particularly immigrant cultures as well as black american cultures actually i'm gonna just
say it's embedded in every culture to be quite honest because we have not existed in a time
where we have centered our emotions as a part of our spirituality and our emotions are literally
our god language they are our spirituality instead we are cut off from them we are told that they are
too extra we are told that they are a problem no your emotions are your ability to communicate with the
the frequencies around you your emotions are are the energy that you combust you think this body is just
combusting like an engine moving a car no your your body is combusting and existing and your emotions
are the energy that it is producing so how could your emotions not be important
it's important for you to understand your emotions and how to not let them control you because you also
need to know how your energy is being controlled of course your emotions can cut you off from certain
frequencies that's why you need to understand them you need to understand the energy that you're putting out
so when someone is saying to you that your emotions are irrelevant let me just say this sometimes your
emotions don't matter to somebody that doesn't mean that your emotions are irrelevant it just means
that they like i'm not really interested in your emotions right now and that's a real thing
so someone followed this up and said i love you for this response the reality is when they have
children the same issues will surface the lesson will be taught until the lesson is learned
i enjoy amanda seals but she has no children and has a supportive mother i want y'all to do me a favor
i want you to stop arguing with people about their parents that's what i want you to do i want you
to listen to people about their parents i see so often when folks say you know i've had to cut off my
father or i've had to distance myself from my mother or something to that effect folks want to do this
like investigative first 48 process where they don't believe you like like that's such an odd concept
where they feel like they need to understand the bottom line the undertone of the truth because
what do you mean your parents aren't good or what do you mean you don't like your parents
for some reason people immediately believe that you are for some reason people automatically think
you're making this up this woman does not know my mother this woman does not know my mother
this woman does not know me let's talk about support
what does support mean a parent supporting your achievements is not the same as supporting
your pitfalls someone supporting your highlights
is not the same as someone supporting your bloopers someone supporting
your wins and not supporting your losses someone supporting
your outward your outward optics but not supporting your inward emotions is not the same
like in my in my for me as an example right so i'm just going to use me as an example
i have a family that has been very supportive of my achievements i have achieved a lot
look at this that's my college degree for undergrad that's best thespian for 1999
this is my high school degree as you can see i'm wearing cords because i was national honor society
i was also in the visual and performing arts magnet this is my plaque from uh columbia university's
master's program in african american studies this is my nomination from the naacp awards for
outstanding supporting actress in the comedy series these are the trademarks for my company smart funny
and black this is a proclamation that i was given by public advocate jumaine williams in brooklyn
for being an artist in advocacy that's my high school diploma and that is my uh degree from columbia
university graduate school of arts and sciences i am an extremely accomplished person it is very
easy to support accomplishment which is also why it's so fucking frustrating when our parents don't
support accomplishment accomplishment is very easy to support what is not so easy to support
is when there is no light and you're in the darkness
and someone has to come through the darkness to hold you and we all find ourselves in the darkness
and we want the people to hold us who brought us from darkness into the light physically that doesn't
always happen however it is an extremely important aspect of existence
to have folks around you who will come find you in the darkness
who don't need to necessarily walk you through the light but will hold your hand
while you figure out how to get back to it those of us who have parents and family
who have left us in the darkness over and over and over and over again know that every single time
they've left us in the dark it's gotten darker we know that we know that then it becomes or it may
have even started this way them pushing you into the darkness the darkness is your shadows
we all have shadows and we all have to find our way to live as the light beings that we are
and anybody whether it's your mother your father your twin your best auntie etc etc anybody
that is not bringing you assistance when your light is dimmed is only keeping you in the darkness
we are light bearing beings light is what gives life
so if we're not able to be in the light then we find ourselves not living
are you understanding what i'm saying my mother is emotionally abusive and has been emotionally
abusing me all my life that does not discount the myriad ways that she has supported me
it does however still exist and i don't care how much somebody supports me in other ways
they don't get to abuse me they don't get to throw me into the darkness
they don't get to leave me there and they don't get to pull me into their own darkness
to avoid having to share space with me and mine
so when we hear people talk about their parents when we hear people talk about their experience with
their family listen to them don't argue don't compare
you might be very fortunate to have a different setup
not all of us have had that
and when people say things like well you don't have kids so you wouldn't understand
it always fascinates me as if i have never been someone's child
perhaps you were an unconscious being
however i was not i have always been an i have always been a conscious being
because when i got here i had already been here
i got here with a clipboard i showed up
all right earth okay so they got this going on on earth
all right i showed up taking notes i have been here before i'm coming back
to report back this woman says she is often viewed as the difficult one
not that i believe she is however she definitely has individualism aspects about her
my guess that her projection my guess that's her projection by being rejected from her various
viewpoints let me also say as complex as she is i do believe she is ahead of her time
i believe her viewpoint here is limited by lack of parental experience similar to oprah
i think some of you all don't seem to grasp that just by having kids it doesn't make you wise
let me say that again simply by having children it does not make you wise
the experience itself does not make you wise
so the effort to diminish people's lived experiences simply because you have done something with your uterus
that they have not is in itself unwise
the concept that being an individual cannot exist in community is a misnomer
that is literally a colonial
distortion of community
colonialism seeks to remove individuality
because if everyone is the same they are easier to control
that is what neurotypical mindsets are
they are controlled
they are minds that are on the same track
so it's like you can literally just flip one switch and all the minds will change
it's like clones
the neurodivergent mindset
the neurodivergent brain is unique
which is why they say if you've met one neurodivergent person
you have met one neurodivergent person
we are on a planet
comprised of drones
and individuals
some would even go so far as to say those drones were made
they were clones that were inserted into society
for the purpose of control
being manifested
and manipulated
I don't know how true that is
at this point I don't put anything past anything
but what I will say
is that your individualism
your individuality
your uniqueness
does not diminish your ability to be in community
your desire
to be seen as the soul that you are
does not diminish you
from being able to be in community
you showed up here
in a body you didn't know
in a world that has been constructed
and you've been trying to figure it out
and you're trying to figure it out
so that you can send messaging
through the DNA
so that maybe these fucking humans
can continue to exist
I'll be damned
if I'm gonna let that mission
be diminished
because of believing in some
nonsense concept of family
that was handed down to me
by people who have never
considered my well-being
so I
I implore you
to support those
who have had to separate
because just because you have to
separate and protect yourself
does not mean it's easy
it does not mean
it is smooth
there are visceral physical reactions
and it requires
so much energy work
and you need
support
so y'all
let's support each other
energetically
expand your consciousness
to be beyond
the limitations
of this shit
that was just given to you
and understand
that support
is more than simply
pat on the back
support can be a leg up
support can be a cradle
support can be silence
in presence
support can be a bar
y'all you can get
this shirt
my art
at amandaline exports
that was a lot of sharing
right now
so I'm gonna have to go cry
about that
and you can
you can show love
to
my work and my art
by subscribing to patreon
where we have conversations
like this all the god dang time
and you can also
go to amandaline exports
to check out the other stuff
the other new items I have
in support of malcolm x
so we have the
malcolm x notepad
I'm pretty proud of this
um and we also have
the classic
malcolm x shirt
um
and the print
that's back there
so I have to go to
um
my cleaners
they just be doing
whatever they want
um
I have to go to an event
later today
and I know people
are gonna be dressed up
you know how I'm gonna be
dressed
I'm dressed up
two days in a row
uh
I can't
I can't do three
I I can't
I can't give them
three days in a row
so
if you see me out today
I'm gonna try
I'm gonna put like a
um
I'm gonna put some glasses on
and some jewelry
or whatever
but this is all they gonna get
this is all they gonna get
and
and also
as for that person
don't ever
mother
fucking compare me
to Oprah Winfrey
don't you
ever in your
life
compare me to
Oprah goddamn
Winfrey
I remember
Boldy James used to
call me the black Oprah
don't you ever in your
life compare me to
Oprah
have a good one
I appreciate you
I hope this conversation
helped you